apnaplan.com 2015-04-16

# Privacy Policy for ApnaPlan | ApnaPlan – Personal Financial Planning and Investing Blog

At [http://apnaplan.com](http://apnaplan.com/), the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by [http://apnaplan.com](http://apnaplan.com/) and how it is used.

### Log Files

Like many other Web sites, [http://apnaplan.com](http://apnaplan.com/) makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. These logs will not be made public unless required by law to do so.

### Cookies and Web Beacons

[http://apnaplan.com](http://apnaplan.com/) does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user access or visit, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include Google Adsense, Infolinks and some other advertisers.

### DoubleClick DART Cookie

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on [http://apnaplan.com](http://apnaplan.com/)
  * Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to [http://apnaplan.com](http://apnaplan.com/) and other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL – <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on [http://apnaplan.com](http://apnaplan.com/) send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

[http://apnaplan.com](http://apnaplan.com/) has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. [http://apnaplan.com](http://apnaplan.com/) privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

**Your Consent**

By using our site, you consent to our web site [privacy policy](http://apnaplan.com/privacy-policy/).

**Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using our [Contact Us Page](http://apnaplan.com/contact-us/)

  * __About the Author
  *  __Latest Posts

  * [What is the Maximum Income Tax You can Save for FY 2015-16?](http://apnaplan.com/max-income-tax-saving-fy2015/) \- April 16, 2015
  * [How good is Credit card against Fixed Deposit?](http://apnaplan.com/credit-card-against-fixed-deposit/) \- April 15, 2015
  * [Highest Interest Rate on Recurring Deposits (RD)](http://apnaplan.com/highest-interest-rate-on-recurring-deposits-rd/) \- April 9, 2015
  * [Tax Planning Guide for FY 2015-16](http://apnaplan.com/tax-guide-fy201516/) \- April 8, 2015
  * [Pepsi IPL 2015 Match Schedule](http://apnaplan.com/pepsi-ipl-2015-match-schedule/) \- April 7, 2015
  * [10.25% SREI Equipment Finance NCD – April 2015 – Should you Invest?](http://apnaplan.com/10-25-srei-equipment-finance-ncd-april-2015-should-you-invest/) \- April 7, 2015
  * [Making Sense of Tax Benefit on Health Insurance u/s 80D](http://apnaplan.com/tax-benefit-health-insurance-sec80d/) \- April 6, 2015
  * [Sukanya Samriddhi interest raised to 9.2% while PPF remains at 8.7% for FY 2015-16](http://apnaplan.com/sukanya-samriddhi-interest-rate-ppf-fy16/) \- April 1, 2015
  * [PPF Calculator for Maturity, Loan and Partial Withdrawal](http://apnaplan.com/ppf-calculator-excel/) \- March 27, 2015
  * [10.8% Muthoot Finance NCD – March/April 2015 – Should you Invest?](http://apnaplan.com/10-8-muthoot-finance-ncd-marchapril-2015-should-you-invest/) \- March 25, 2015
